<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latest News | QuantLab 2.0</title>
    <link>http://maacevedo.github.io/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://maacevedo.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Latest News</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://maacevedo.github.io/media/logo_hu27752b9ce9aca15dbd0b2a53e0ef7be8_12580069_300x300_fit_lanczos_3.png</url>
      <title>Latest News</title>
      <link>http://maacevedo.github.io/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orlando wins UF-CALS and an international teaching award</title>
      <link>http://maacevedo.github.io/post/24_09_15_wec_orlando/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://maacevedo.github.io/post/24_09_15_wec_orlando/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Orlando wins yet another two awards!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our lab is very proud of Orlando. He won two awards this summer including the Lowe Scholar from UF-CALS and the Graduate Student Teaching Award from the North America Colleges and Teachers of Agriculture (NACTA). We are very proud of Orlando and his accomplishments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bella wins Best Oral Presentation</title>
      <link>http://maacevedo.github.io/post/24_09_10_wec_bella/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://maacevedo.github.io/post/24_09_10_wec_bella/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bella wins yet another award!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our lab is very proud of Bella. She won the &lt;em&gt;2024 Outstanding Student Oral Presentation Award&lt;/em&gt; at the 10th Annual World Congress of Herpetology. Bella presented her work titled  &lt;em&gt;Welcome to Miami: Reproductive Traits and Pathogen Potential of Introduced Caecilians (Typhlonectes Natans) in Florida&lt;/em&gt;. Bella is an undergraduate researcher in our lab group, but also in other labs at UF. She presented work that she conducted as part of &lt;a href=&#34;https://thelongolab.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Ana Longo&amp;rsquo;s Lab&lt;/a&gt; in Biology. We are big fans of Bella and Dr. Longo&amp;rsquo;s group.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computational/Quantitative Ecology Postdoc</title>
      <link>http://maacevedo.github.io/post/24_04_30_quant_ecol_postdoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://maacevedo.github.io/post/24_04_30_quant_ecol_postdoc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are looking for a post-doctoral researcher to join our Snail Kite research team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TITLE&lt;/strong&gt;: Postdoctoral Researcher (Computational/Quantitative Ecology and Conservation)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LOCATION&lt;/strong&gt;: University of Florida, Gainesville, Florida. We will consider remote working arrangements for exceptional candidates who need to be based in a different location for a small part of their appointment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SALARY&lt;/strong&gt;: Starting salary approximately $50,000, with a competitive benefits package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DURATION&lt;/strong&gt;: The initial appointment will be for one year, with the possibility of renewal for a second year pending satisfactory performance and availability of funds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;START DATE&lt;/strong&gt;: Flexible, but preferably by June 15, 2024. The position will be open until filled&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RESPONSIBILITIES&lt;/strong&gt;: The University of Florida Snail Kite research group is seeking a postdoctoral researcher with expertise in data engineering and/or data science applied to ecology and conservation. The successful candidate will work as part of a large, long-term research project on spatial ecology, population biology, and conservation of an endangered raptor, the Everglade Snail Kite. This project is unparalleled in spatial population biology and conservation by providing rigorous demographic and movement information across the entire breeding range of this critically imperiled species for the past 25 years, which is used for management, restoration, and conservation. This postdoctoral researcher is expected to (1) develop effective data management workflows for long-term monitoring data, (2) conduct a population viability analysis, (3) and develop novel applied research on the ecology and conservation of Florida Snail Kites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;QUALIFICATIONS&lt;/strong&gt;:
•	A PhD in ecology, biology, statistics, or applied mathematics completed by the position start date.
•	Strong computational skills including data management, data wrangling, and database management systems.
•	Programming experience (R and/or Python)
•	A demonstrated track record of analyzing complex ecological data
•	The ability to work independently and as part of an interdisciplinary team; a strong work ethic and commitment to reproducible and open science.
•	Desired (but not required) skills include experience with population modeling, capture-mark-recapture, and population viability analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To apply&lt;/strong&gt;: Please send (1) a cover letter summarizing your research interests and relevant experience, (2) a Curriculum Vitae, and (3) contact information for three references to Miguel Acevedo (&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:maacevedo@ufl.edu&#34;&gt;maacevedo@ufl.edu&lt;/a&gt;) and Rob Fletcher (&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:robert.fletcher@ufl.edu&#34;&gt;robert.fletcher@ufl.edu&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last day to apply: The position will remain open until filled. Review of applications will begin on May 20, 2024, and will continue until the position is filled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About Gainesville, Florida&lt;/strong&gt;: Situated in the rolling countryside of north-central Florida, Gainesville is much more than a stereotypical college town. Home of the University of Florida, seat of Alachua County&amp;rsquo;s government and the region&amp;rsquo;s commercial hub, it is progressive, environmentally conscious, and culturally diverse. The presence of many students and faculty from abroad among its 99,000-plus population adds a strong cross-cultural flavor to its historic small-town Southern roots. Its natural environment, temperate climate, and civic amenities make Gainesville a beautiful, pleasant, and interesting place in which to learn and live. Gainesville has been ranked as one of the best cities to live in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WEC 2024 Awards</title>
      <link>http://maacevedo.github.io/post/24_04_26_wec_awards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://maacevedo.github.io/post/24_04_26_wec_awards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Orlando and Bella won awards during the 2024 WEC BBQ!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our lab is very proud of Orlando and Bella. Orlando won the &lt;em&gt;2024 Outstanding Graduate Student of the year&lt;/em&gt; award and Bella won the &lt;em&gt;2024 Outstanding Professional Promise&lt;/em&gt; award. Orlando and Bella inspire all us. Their passion for science and ecology is conspicuous and contagious. We are lucky to have them on our lab group. Keep up the good work!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our work is featured in the cover of Ecological Applications</title>
      <link>http://maacevedo.github.io/post/24-04-01-ecological_applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://maacevedo.github.io/post/24-04-01-ecological_applications/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of our favorite anoles made it to the cover of &lt;em&gt;Ecological Applications&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are super happy to share that our paper titled &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.doi.org/10.1002/eap.2960&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Recolonization of secondary forests by a locally extinct Caribbean anole through the lens of range expansion theory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; made it to the cover of the journal Ecological Applications. Recovering forests are becoming a prevalent characteristic of the Anthropocene landscape, particularly in the tropics. Some of these recovering forests provide the minimum requirements for the recolonization of fauna. In this study we study this process of fauna recolonization through the lens of range expansion. We compared phenotypic traits, population dynamics, and parasitism rates of a shade-specialist anole (&lt;em&gt;Anolis gundlachi&lt;/em&gt;) among forests of different ages in Puerto Rico. Our results show that animals in young forests have unique phenotypic traits, lower densities, and suffer less parasitism rates, as predicted by range expansion theory. This was a highly collaborative study including many graduate and undergraduate researchers in our group. We are excited to show off this beautiful anole in the cover the journal. Look at that beautiful blue eyes!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Undergraduate research team presentation</title>
      <link>http://maacevedo.github.io/post/24_04_01_undergraduate_research_symp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://maacevedo.github.io/post/24_04_01_undergraduate_research_symp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Undergraduate research team presented in the UF Undergraduate Research Symposium&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our undergraduate research team presented the results of their work on the effects of hurricane disturbance on phenotypic traits of the anole &lt;em&gt;Anolis stratulus&lt;/em&gt;, one of the most common anole species at El Verde Field Station in Puerto Rico. They analyzed six years of data to show that the size of lizards captured after the hurricane increased. They described a series of hypotheses that may explain this pattern including the potential vertical redistribution of anole species following hurricane disturbance. Good job Julia, Brooke, Bella, Vic and Cooper!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carly defended her MS thesis</title>
      <link>http://maacevedo.github.io/post/23-12-08-carly_graduation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://maacevedo.github.io/post/23-12-08-carly_graduation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to Carly for the successful defense of her MS thesis!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are super happy to announce that Carly successfully defended her thesis titled &lt;em&gt;ECO-EVOLUTIONARY DYNAMICS OF A THERMOCONFORMING ANOLE RECOLONIZING SECONDARY FOREST&lt;/em&gt;. For her thesis she compared genomic diversity and structure of &lt;em&gt;Anolis gundlachi&lt;/em&gt; among forests of different ages in Puerto Rico. She also collaborated in multiple other projects in our lab and co-authored three peer-reviewed publications.  We wish her the very best in her future endeavors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Matt, Brynn and Megan presented in the undergraduate research symposium</title>
      <link>http://maacevedo.github.io/post/23_11_08_back_undergrad_symp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://maacevedo.github.io/post/23_11_08_back_undergrad_symp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our undergraduate research team presented their research&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many studies on habitat-species relationships evaluate the role of habitat variables using buffers of certain sizes. Still, what is the optimal size? Megan, Matt, Brynn and Orlando have been working to estimate what is the optimal scale to quantify species-habitat relationships in a group of tropical birds from the genus &lt;em&gt;Thraupis&lt;/em&gt; using eBird data. Their preliminary results suggest that&amp;hellip;one size may not fit all. Good job team!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations Dr. Gengler</title>
      <link>http://maacevedo.github.io/post/23_08_12_congratulations_nick/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://maacevedo.github.io/post/23_08_12_congratulations_nick/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nick just graduated from his PhD! Congratulations Dr. Gengler!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nick initial PhD idea was to work on quantitative approaches to better understand and manage mammal communities in Paraguay. And then COVID19 happened. He couldn&amp;rsquo;t travel to Paraguay so instead, Nick developed a pretty clever plan b, to address one of the most important challenges in landscape ecology. As part of his dissertation Nick conducted a global analysis compare the scale of effect of landscape composition and configuration of forest mammals. Nick&amp;rsquo;s degree was supported by an (NSF-GRF)[https://www.nsfgrfp.org/]. We are grateful of NSF for supporting his career. Paraguay didn&amp;rsquo;t happened for his PhD, but&amp;hellip;he landed a position with local NGO in Paraguay working in mammal conservation. Nick&amp;rsquo;s story is one of perseverance and success.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Papers 2.0 (ESA 2023)</title>
      <link>http://maacevedo.github.io/post/23_08_11_data_papers_esa/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://maacevedo.github.io/post/23_08_11_data_papers_esa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are back from Portland, where we did a workshop on Data Papers and the future of open science at ESA 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The future of ecology is intrinsically tied to our ability to conduct open science. Data Papers are a special type of paper in Ecology where data and metadata are published to be reused. Our group of ESA Data Paper Editors composed of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.usgs.gov/index.php/staff-profiles/grace-v-direnzo&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Grace DiRenzo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://haoye.us/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Hao Ye&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.picardiecology.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Simona Picardi&lt;/a&gt;, and myself are working towards a re conceptualization of this important type of paper. We are following a data-driven process that includes gathering input from the community. As part of this process we led a special session at ESA where our community engaged in a super fun and highly engaging brainstorming session. Working with this group is a real luxury! Stay tuned as we we will announce soon the new features of Data Papers 2.0!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miguel gets NACTA Educators Award</title>
      <link>http://maacevedo.github.io/post/23-07-01-nacta-award/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://maacevedo.github.io/post/23-07-01-nacta-award/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to Miguel for getting the NACTA Educator Award recognition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;North American Colleges and Teachers of Agriculture (NACTA) recognized Miguel with the NACTA Educator Award which recognizes those individuals whose efforts represent the very best in agricultural higher education.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We are back from Puerto Rico (Summer 2023)</title>
      <link>http://maacevedo.github.io/post/23_05_01_back_from_puerto_rico/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://maacevedo.github.io/post/23_05_01_back_from_puerto_rico/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are back from the field collecting data on lizard malaria in Puerto Rico.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was an awesome and productive field season! Our first mission was to collect data for our long-term study of lizard-malaria dynamics. (Yes, lizards get malaria. No, you will not likely get malaria from a lizard). One of the biggest mysteries in this system is the vector identity. We know that malaria gets transmitted among lizards by an insect vector, but we don&amp;rsquo;t know who it is. This field season, we brought the big guns! We joined forces with &lt;a href=&#34;https://yeemosquitolab.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Don Yee&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lawrencereeves.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Lawrence Reeves&lt;/a&gt;&amp;hellip;and&amp;hellip;during a night walk we finally saw our suspected vector biting lizards! We are working as a team to report our findings in a peer-reviewed publication. Needless to say that we are super excited about the discovery!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We are back from Mitu</title>
      <link>http://maacevedo.github.io/post/23_04_01_back_from_mitu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://maacevedo.github.io/post/23_04_01_back_from_mitu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are back from the Colombian Amazon in an expedition to assess Orlando&amp;rsquo;s study sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Amazon&amp;hellip;did we need to say more?! What a fantastic expedition. We spent nine days in Vaupés, Colombia-one of the most isolated parts of the Colombian Amazon where Orlando wants to do one of the chapters of his dissertation. We were joined by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.floridamuseum.ufl.edu/museum-voices/scott-robinson/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Scott Robinson&lt;/a&gt; so&amp;hellip;yes&amp;hellip;we were interested in those hyper diverse bird communities, particularly those that lived white sand forests. Orlando&amp;rsquo;s questions about climate change and bird-species assemblages in the Amazon are timely, the study site magical, and the local indigenous communities welcoming. We can&amp;rsquo;t wait to be back!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
